<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Linux on Int Maker</title>
    <link>https://intmaker.com/categories/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Linux on Int Maker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 13:26:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://intmaker.com/categories/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependency-driven development: forced OSS contributions</title>
      <link>https://intmaker.com/forced-oss-contributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2017 13:26:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://intmaker.com/forced-oss-contributions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is such a relief when you app just works. Moreover, when it is open. My pet project &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/ribtoks/xpiks&#34;&gt;Xpiks&lt;/a&gt; is not only an open-source project itself, but it also uses a lot of the other open-source technologies inside. Qt framework, zlib, hunspell - to name just a few. A big deal is to make them work together. A much bigger deal to make them work together across different platforms (Xpiks is announced as cross-platform for Windows, OS X and Linux). The least problems you can expect - is a tricky build process or somebody&amp;rsquo;s typo in the Makefile which breaks the-other-system&amp;rsquo;s build.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More often what you&amp;rsquo;ll encounter - is people building a huge pile of code working &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; for their needs. Only for their server. Only for their version if libcurl. Only for x86 operating system. And then they open-source it to GitHub - much like a cemetery for projects with 1 star and 0 forks, decaying there until forgotten forever.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how the initial joy of finding an open-source technology you needed is being replaced by a constant frustration of not just a need to slightly tweak some header file or Makefile, but to go the sources, read them, understand everything inside and fix. This is what I have encountered many times and what I did as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple Gimp plugin for batch processing in Python</title>
      <link>https://intmaker.com/gimp-plugin-batch-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 11:32:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://intmaker.com/gimp-plugin-batch-processing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not so far ago I needed to batch-process some images. The task was to resize them so they fit to given smallest resolution. Although Gimp has some batch-processing plugins, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to solve my problem with them. That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;ve invented small little bike and I&amp;rsquo;d like to share with you workarounds and explanations of some Gimp plug-in development issues.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Your plugin can take as little as just one python file with call to function &lt;em&gt;register&lt;/em&gt; (&lt;em&gt;from gimpfu&lt;/em&gt;) and passing to it some metadata and actual method of plugin. You can read more about parameters to register on &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;official docs website&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. But a few moments still need clarifications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TeamCity 8 on CentOS 6.4 from scratch</title>
      <link>https://intmaker.com/teamcity-8-on-centos-from-scratch/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2013 16:22:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://intmaker.com/teamcity-8-on-centos-from-scratch/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this post I&amp;rsquo;ll describe whole TeamCity installation process on a fresh CentOS (on the moment I&amp;rsquo;m writing it&amp;rsquo;s 6.4) for your private project or startup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, proceed to the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;CentOS downloads page&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; and download CentOS distro through &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.iso&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;, &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.torrent&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; or &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;whatever-you-like&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; and start the installation process. If you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with any  linux distro installation, it won&amp;rsquo;t take you much time to complete the installation. I&amp;rsquo;m using the minimal configuration without any Desktop Environment and with minimum core- and other system utils. Nonetheless, consider installing &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;iptables, elinks and java (openjdk)&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the installation is over, login, add a user for yourself with &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;adduser&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; and let&amp;rsquo;s start with TeamCity (maybe you&amp;rsquo;ll also consider adding yourself to the sudoers file).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, create &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;/opt/jetbrains/&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; directory and &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;download latest TeamCity&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; using &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;wget&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;mkdir /opt/jetbrains
cd /opt/jetbrains
wget http://download.jetbrains.com/teamcity/TeamCity-8.0.5.tar.gz
tar -xpzf TeamCity-8.0.5.tar.gz
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now lets create a system user (e.g. no home directory) for TeamCity to resolve security issues correctly:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;adduser -r teamcity
passwd teamcity
chown -R teamcity:teamcity TeamCity
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll use PostgreSQL for the internal database for TeamCity. So let&amp;rsquo;s install postgresql packages (8.4 for CentOS 6.4). For details of the PostgreSQL installation please refer to &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;official webpage&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;yum install postgresql
service postgresql initdb
chkconfig postgresql on
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Also edit the &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;/var/lib/pgsql/data/pg_hba.conf&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; file to allow authorization from &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;localhost&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;. Go to the end and replace &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;ident&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; to &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;trust&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; for &lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt;localhost&lt;!-- raw HTML omitted --&gt; in the configuration for hosts. Now lets create another user for the future TeamCity database and create a database for that user.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre style=&#34;background-color:#fff;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-shell&#34; data-lang=&#34;shell&#34;&gt;sudo -u postgres psql postgres
password postgres
sudo -u postgres createuser -D -A -P teamcity_user
sudo -u postgres createdb -O teamcity_user teamcity_db
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;(D = Cannot create databases, A = Cannot add users, P = Force password prompt)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MediaWiki installation on a linux guest in the VirtualBox: how-to, tips &amp; tricks</title>
      <link>https://intmaker.com/mediawiki-installation-virtualbox/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2013 18:51:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://intmaker.com/mediawiki-installation-virtualbox/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve spend half of a day trying to get MediaWiki working on a VirtualBox for the internal project in the internal network. Looks like it&amp;rsquo;s done now and I want to share tips to help someone to spend less time in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been installing and configuring MediaWiki 1.21 on the OpenSUSE 12.3, but all tips are valuable for any linux distro.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>