<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>embedded on Int Maker</title>
    <link>https://intmaker.com/tags/embedded/</link>
    <description>Recent content in embedded on Int Maker</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:21:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://intmaker.com/tags/embedded/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuller Stack Development</title>
      <link>https://intmaker.com/2018/fuller-stack-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2018 00:21:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://intmaker.com/2018/fuller-stack-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s awesome how many Full-Stack Developers are out there nowadays: full Node.js stack or ASP.NET or what not is popular. However, this is a story of a completely different &amp;ldquo;stack&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I truly believe that software-only engineers somewhere deep inside are always dreaming of pilgrimage to the sacred temples of Hardware and Electronics. All those wires, volts, chips and firmware are just too interesting to avoid them when you only deal with computers above the Transport layer. Basically that&amp;rsquo;s how I was seduced to the dark side, on my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I has already been looking for a possibility to do something &amp;ldquo;forbidden&amp;rdquo; for quite some time. Words like soldering, Arduino, IO pins, &amp;ldquo;10K resistor before LED&amp;rdquo; were constantly spinning in my head but I didn&amp;rsquo;t have just any time for it. Luckily, this month my brother was going to visit me for a week so I decided it would be a perfect time to do some hacking together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apparently it was hard to come up with an idea of what exactly to do. Of course, I wanted to do something &amp;ldquo;special&amp;rdquo; right ahead but I had to admit I didn&amp;rsquo;t have any basic knowledge about that stuff. After some research I decided to start with something simple: to create first iteration of &amp;ldquo;smart home&amp;rdquo;. Particularly I wanted to know &lt;strong&gt;what temperature is in every room of the apartment I live in&lt;/strong&gt;. And plan to implement that was the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arduino will read temperature with sensor DHT22 and send data with 433MHz module&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi will receive data with 433MHz module and save it to DB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Raspberry Pi will serve simple website where you can see the data&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;once that will work, create &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; sensor based on Arduino Mini&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key-Value storage for poor</title>
      <link>https://intmaker.com/2017/key-value-storage-for-poor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2017 11:30:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://intmaker.com/2017/key-value-storage-for-poor/</guid>
      <description>Despite the hype about NoSql databases, sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s nice to have an embedded key-value storage available in your app. For example, I&amp;rsquo;m maintaining a cache of metadata of images in my cross-platform desktop app Xpiks and anyway I have to search by filepath to find the metadata. Besides that I have few more requirements specific to my project:
 the database should be possible to embed directly into your app the license should allow linking with proprietary code (so to be either permissive MIT, BSD-like or LGPL) it should be cross-platform in a sense of Windows, macOS and Linux it should have a history of being used across various projects (sort of to be 5+ years old) it should be affordable to get, since I&amp;rsquo;m not a big company or any sort of company  So when I started looking for this sort of databases, first thing I found was Berkeley DB.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>